Shashank Shekhar

Bangalore, Karnataka , India +91 9891481443 shashankforworkshekhar@gmail.com

Professional Summary.

6+ years of experience in software development and engineering encompassing software development(full stack), DevOps, cloud computing, automation, and on-premise/cloud production support. Proficient in web technologies, specializing in serverless applications with Node.js and .NET, interactive web applications using frameworks like React and Angular, and automation with Go and Python. Delivered Production grade application on both AWS and Azure cloud Platforms.

Skills

- Languages:
 - Proficiency in : Javascript, Typescript.
 - o **Familiarity with**: C#, Python 3, Go
- Development Frameworks: Node, React, Angular, Serverless, Express, Next, Fibre, Nest, Dot Net MVC
- Databases: Postgres, MariaDB, SSMS, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Redis
- Devops and Automation: Docker, Kubernetes, BitBucket Pipelines, YAML, Github Actions, AWS CodePipelines
- Command Line Scripting: Bash, AWS CLI, Powershell
- Cloud Services:
 - o AWS Lambdas , DynamoDB, RDS, Glue
 - o Azure AKS, Azure Functions, Ingress

Experience

Feb 2024 - Present

NTT Data, Inc (Previously NTT Ltd), Bangalore - Senior Software Development Engineer

- E2E Design Development and Testing of Inhouse Platform.
- Manage scaling and Integrations of product by closely working with Vendors from EMEA,
 APAC and Americas
- Train and onboard new team members.

Jun 2021 - Feb 2024

Winjit Technologies, Bangalore - Senior Software Engineer

E2E Design Development and Testing of Production Grader Cloud Native (AWS)
 Applications

- Designing and Developing fault tolerance and resilient systems in monolithic, n-tier and microservice architecture
- Setting up CI CD pipeline for deployments and working with Serverless Framework to improve Cloud Integration .
- Consuming various cloud services including AWS EC2, AWS cloudfront, Cloudwatch S3
 Aurora, Document DB etc.
- Design and create Relational and Non Relational Databases along with Cache management systems using Mysql, Postgres, Mong DB, Redis etc.
- Working with Cloud Native Databases like Dynamo DB and DocumentDB.
- Responsible for Code Optimization Load testing and Site reliability testing.

Nov 2018 - June 2021

NTT Data, Bangalore - Software development senior associate

- Development and release of cross platform desktop applications with web technologies.
- Developing deploying and Maintaining automation based web applications.
- Writing various automation workflow using powershell and low code RPA platforms
- Production support with a large catalog of applications, including Change management, Service request resolution, incident management and Problem management.

Sept 2018 - Nov 2018

CherishTrip Pvt Ltd, Gurugram - Business Intelligence Freelance Consultant

- Automated data fetching and sorting
- Data visualization and Report generation for the sales team.
- Data analysis using Numpy and Pandas

Education

Sept 2014 - Jun 2018

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University , New Delhi - Bachelors of Technology in Electronic and Communications Engineering

Awards

2 X Rising Star awarded by Winjit Technologies

3 X Star Performer awarded by NTT Data Pvt Ltd.